Guide to the Joel Garreau Papers, 1954-1994
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 2: The Nine Nations of North America, November 1954-February 1987
  - Subseries 2.8: The Empty Quarter, March 1972-November 1985
    - La Quartier Desert, Undated (Box 61, Folder 12)
      The Empty Quarter chapter from the French edition of "Nine Nations".
  - Subseries 2.9: The Breadbasket, May 1965-December 1979
    Documents from Garreau's "Nine Nations" files about "The Breadbasket" section of the book. The nation includes most of the prairie states and part of the pare provinces with a capital at Kansas City, Kansas.
    - Oklahoma 1 of 3, April-December 1979 (Box 61, Folder 13)
      Articles, notes and mailings about culture, labor, crime, immigration and the history of Oklahoma.
    - Oklahoma 2 of 3, May 1965-August 1979 (Box 61, Folder 14)
      Pamphlets, census reports, notes, book excerpts and articles about crime, real estate, sports, culture and history in Oklahoma. Also included are population sketches of parts of Oklahoma and a transcript of the impeachment of Oklahoma state supreme court justices.
    - Oklahoma 3 of 3, Undated (Box 61, Folder 15)
      Book excerpts and notes about Oklahoma.
    - La Corbeille a Pain, Undated (Box 61, Folder 16)
      The Breadbasket chapter of the French edition of "Nine Nations".
  - Subseries 2.10: Quebec, March 1974-October 1980
    Documents from Garreau's "Nine Nations" files about the "Quebec" section of the book. The nation includes the primarily French-speaking province of Canada with a capital at Quebec City. Many of the documents in this series are in French.
    - Quebec, March 1974-1980 (Box 62, Folder 1)
      Pamphlets, correspondence, notes, magazines and articles about Quebecois nationalism, energy production, business, politics, education and crime.
    - Quebec 1 of 3, September 1978-June 1980 (Box 62, Folder 2)
      Notes, correspondence and articles about Quebecois and Canadian nationalism, economy, natural resources, energy production, business, diversity and history.
    - Quebec 2 of 3, September 1978-September 1980 (Box 62, Folder 3)
      Articles and magazines about Quebecois nationalism, politics, newspapers and energy production. Also included is "Ethnic Segmentation, Loyalties, Incentives and Constitutional OPtions in Quebec" by Maurice Pinard.
    - Quebec 3 of 3, May 1978-October 1980 (Box 62, Folder 4)
      Articles, pamphlets and notes about Quebecois and Canadian nationalism, business, education, politics, advertising, transportation, history and energy production.
    - Le Quebec, Undated (Box 62, Folder 5)
      The Quebec chapter of the French edition of "Nine Nations".
  - Subseries 2.11: Television, February 1977-October 1986
    Documents from Garreau's "Nine Nations" files about a proposed 10 part television program based on "Nine Nations".
    - Notes on TV Proposal, December 1981-November 1985 (Box 62, Folder 6)
      Correspondence, notes and articles about Mexican industry, and a summary of Nine Nations.
    - TV Negotiation, August 1981-May 1983 (Box 62, Folder 7)
      Correspondence about and contracts from the negotiation of the Nine Nations television program. Also included are articles, business cards and notes about television.
    - Nine Nations Proposal 1 of 5, February 1977-October 1986 (Box 62, Folder 8)
      Documents, notes, correspondence, interview transcripts and articles about documentaries, television production companies, television producers and Mexican politics.
    - Nine Nations Proposal 2 of 5, February-September 1985 (Box 62, Folder 9)
      Notes, proposal drafts and correspondence about the proposed pilot about MexAmerica for the Nine Nations program, other material includes draft contracts and maps.
    - Nine Nations Proposal 3 of 5, August 1981-October 1985 (Box 63, Folder 1)
      Articles, proposal drafts, notes and correspondence about television producers and production companies, Mexican Politics, the Nine Nations book and the proposed television program.
    - Nine Nations Proposal 4 of 5, June-October 1985 (Box 63, Folder 2)
      Articles and notes about Mexican development and economy, correspondence about the proposal for the Nine Nations television program, and the actual proposal. Also included are event schedules and registration forms and an article about North American ethnic cuisine.
    - Nine Nations Proposal 5 of 5, June 1983-April 1986 (Box 63, Folder 3)
      Articles about culture and business in the border area between Mexico and the United States, correspondence draft and actual proposals for the television program. Also included is a profile of the state of Connecticut.
    - Notes on TV Deal, August 1985 (Box 63, Folder 4)
      Notes and contracts for the Nine Nations television program.
    - Television Project, September 1984 (Box 63, Folder 5)
      Notes and correspondence about the Nine Nations television program and other like it.
    - The Nine Nations of North America, Undated (Box 63, Folder 6)
      The proposal for the Nine Nations television program.
    - The Washington Post, April 1986 (Box 63, Folder 7)
      A rough draft of a proposal for the Nine Nations television program.
    - The Nine Nations of North America 1 of 2, February 1985 (Box 63, Folder 8)
      Notes, draft proposals, maps and articles about the Nine Nations television program, world history and demographics.
    - The Nine Nations of North America 2 of 2, Undated (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - The Carver Group, July 1985 (Box 63, Folder 10)
      Correspondence about the Nine Nations television program.
  - Subseries 2.12: Miscellaneous, July 1969-October 1985
    Miscellaneous documents from Garreau's "Nine Nations" files.
    - Correspondents 1 of 3, July 1969-November 1984 (Box 63, Folder 11)
      Correspondence, notes, articles, maps and other documents about Nine Nations, regionalism, tests and power production. Also included is documents from New York Telephone Public Talks Program.
    - Correspondents 2 of 3, February 1983-February 1985 (Box 63, Folder 12)
      Correspondence, notes and articles about regionalism, arctic policy, Joel Garreau and Nine Nations. Also included is an information packet about a documentary called "Ballad of an Unsung Hero".
    - Correspondents 3 of 3, July 1981-October 1985 (Box 63, Folder 13)
      Correspondence to and from Garreau about his work. Also included is The 1983 annual report from the Construction Industry Manufacturers Association, "The Late Great State" by Oliver Hailey, articles and maps.
    - Folklife Center News, January-June 1985 (Box 64, Folder 1)
      Two issues of Folklife Center News from the Library of Congress.
    - Crown, December 1984 (Box 64, Folder 2)
      An issue of Crown, the Hallmark Magazine.
    - The Demographics of Women, March 1985 (Box 64, Folder 3)
      The March 1985 issue of American Demographics magazine.
    - Speaking Contract, March-April 1984 (Box 64, Folder 4)
      Correspondence about a speaking engagement in which Garreau participated.
    - The Interpretation of Reality, Undated (Box 64, Folder 5)
      An essay by D. Park Teter titled "The Interpretation of Reality".
    - The American Express, April 1981 (Box 64, Folder 6)
      A newsletter for American Express cardholders featuring an article about technology and communication.
    - Miscellaneous, November 1983-August 1984 (Box 64, Folder 7)
      Notes, correspondence and other documents about regionalism, also included is the Midwest Research Institute 1983 annual report.
    - American Studies Seminar, April-August 1984 (Box 64, Folder 8)
      The syllabus, schedule of events and newsletter about an American Studies seminar at the University of Minnesota.
    - Edward M. Griffin, 1985 (Box 64, Folder 9)
      The professional summary of Edward M. Griffin and a postcard from Minneapolis, Minnesota.
    - Addison-Wesley, May 1985 (Box 64, Folder 10)
      An information packet from Addison-Wesley publishing group about the tour of Robert Kelley, who wrote "The Gold-Collar Worker".
    - Contact information, May 1979-February 1984 (Box 64, Folder 11)
      Phone numbers, business cards, correspondence, notes and addresses. Also included is a restaurant menu.
    - Joel's Personal Letters, December 1977-February 1985 (Box 64, Folder 12)
      Correspondence written to Joel Garreau.
    - Public Opinion, December 1983-January 1984 (Box 64, Folder 13)
      The Dec/Jan 1984 issue of Public Opinion magazine.
    - The Christian Science Monitor Travel Section, March 1984 (Box 64, Folder 14)
      An article about traveling in the United States.
    - Alfonso Flex, Jr., March 1982 (Box 64, Folder 15)
      A letter from Alfonso Flex, Jr. to Morton Netzorg
    - The University of Wyoming, October 1981 (Box 64, Folder 16)
      A letter to Garreau from Gene M. Gressley, the director of the Archive of Contemporary History at the University of Wyoming about the history of journalism.
    - Communications Technology, June-November 1979 (Box 64, Folder 17)
      Articles and magazines about radio stations, computers, telephones and television.
    - The Nine Nations of North America, Undated (Box 64, Folder 18)
      Maps and descriptions of the nine nations of North America.